birchbox.com 2017-01-30

# Privacy Policy | Birchbox

Birchbox Inc. (“Birchbox”, “we” or “us”), the operator of this web site, developer and operator of this Application, and operator of this Retail Store, is committed to preserving the privacy of those who visit the [www.birchbox.com](https://birchbox.com/) site (the “Site”), who download and use the Birchbox Application (the “App”), and who visit and shop at our Retail Store located at 433 West Broadway New York, NY 10012 (the “Store”). This document will outline how we gather and utilize various sources of information obtained during your visit to the Site, App, and Store. We adhere to the Safe Harbor Agreement concerning the transfer of personal data from the European Union (“EU”) to the United States of America. Accordingly, we follow the Safe Harbor Principles published by the [U.S. Department of Commerce](https://safeharbor.export.gov/list.aspx) (the “Principles”) with respect to all such data. If there is any conflict between the Policies in this privacy policy and the Principles, the Principles shall govern. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected on the Site, in the App, and at the Store and is made a part of and incorporated into the Terms and Conditions for the Site, App, and Store.

This Privacy Policy communicates how, when, and why we gather information about our customers and what we do with it.

**THIS PRIVACY POLICY DOES NOT APPLY TO OTHER WEBSITES TO WHICH WE LINK. YOU AGREE THAT YOUR USE OF THE SITE, APP, AND STORE SIGNIFIES YOUR ASSENT TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU ARE NOT AUTHORIZED TO USE THIS SITE, APP, AND STORE.**

### Information Collected

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

If you subscribe to Birchbox and/or place an order through Birchbox.com, sign up and/or place an order through the App, or subscribe and/or place an order through the Store we will ask you for your name, e-mail address, shipping address, telephone number and credit card information or certain other personally identifiable information about yourself ("Personal Information").

We use this information to process and fulfill your order and to notify you of your order status. All archived credit card information is maintained in a secure and safe environment. Telephone numbers and e-mail addresses are used to contact you regarding your order. In addition, when you respond to a contest, survey, questionnaire, sweepstakes or other promotional feature, we may ask you for your name, address and email address or other Personal Information. We do not collect any Personal Information about you unless it is voluntarily provided by you. **Birchbox will never sell, rent or share your Personal Information, including your e-mail address, with any third parties for marketing purposes without your express permission.**

#### NON-PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

In addition, we may also collect non-personally identifiable information, such as IP host address, pages viewed, browser type, duration and frequency of visits, and other data, and may aggregate any information collected in a manner which does not identify any individual ("Aggregate Information"). Information obtained in connection with the Site, the App, and the Store may be intermingled with and used by us in conjunction with information obtained through sources other than the, Site, App, and Store including both offline and online sources.

### How We Use Your Information

We will not share or disclose your information to anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### ENHANCED AND PERSONALIZED SHOPPING EXPERIENCE

We use Personal Information in order to give you a more enjoyable convenient shopping experience and to help us identify and/or provide information, products or services that may be of interest to you. We use your Personal Information to support and enhance your use of the Site, and its features, the App, and the Store, including without limitation: fulfilling your order; providing customer service; tracking email invitations you send; and otherwise supporting your use of the Site, App, and Store.

We may also track your past purchases to provide you with a personalized profile of your shopping history. In addition, we may notify you about new services or special promotional programs, or send you offers or information. In connection with their performance of services to maintain and operate the Site, the App, and the Store and certain features on the Site, the App, and the Store, certain trusted third parties may be permitted to access your information. For example, we may use third parties to host the Site; operate various features available on the Site and the App; send emails; analyze data; provide search results and links and assist in fulfilling your orders.

#### AFFILIATES; CONSULTANTS; THIRD PARTIES

Unless you specifically consent to the disclosure of your Personal Information, aside from us, only our affiliates, technical consultants, third party auditors and other third parties who make our Site, App, and Store available, enhance its functionality, assist with the processing of your purchases, or provide associated services and/or who deal with you in delivering content, samples, products, gifts and prizes, have access to this information, and we require them to agree that they are covered by this policy.

#### LAW ENFORCEMENT AND INVESTIGATIONS

Please note that Birchbox reserves the right to and may disclose Personal Information about you in response to (a) requests from local, state or federal law enforcement officials; (b) any judicial, administrative or similar proceeding or order, such as subpoena; (c) if required by law; or (d) to investigate suspected fraud, harassment, physical threats, or other violations of any law, rule or regulation, the Site, App, or Store rules or policies, or the rights of third parties or to investigate any suspected conduct which we deem improper.

#### CHANGE OF CONTROL

Please also note that we do reserve the right to transfer your Personal Information and other information as an asset in connection with a proposed or actual merger or sale (including any transfers made as part of an insolvency or bankruptcy proceeding) involving all or part of our business or as part of a corporate reorganization, stock sale or other change in control. In such a circumstance the Transferee would be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy.

#### SWEEPSTAKES

If you submit your email address to be added to a mailing list or Sweepstakes or other promotion, we will use the email address for the sole purpose of sending you announcements, special offers from Birchbox and its promotional partners along with Site, App, and Store updates. Each email we send will contain information on how to unsubscribe from our mailing list. You can also unsubscribe by sending an email to info@birchbox.com.

#### REFERRALS

If you elect to use our referral services for informing a friend about our Site, App, or Store we ask you for the friend's name and email address. Birchbox will automatically send the friend an initial email inviting them to visit or transact with the Site. Birchbox may also send additional emails reminding your friend that you referred them. Additionally, you may send additional "Nudges" to your friend to remind them to sign up. Birchbox stores this information for the sole purpose of sending these referral emails and tracking the success of our referral program. The friend may contact Birchbox at to request the removal of this information from our database and to stop receiving Nudges.

### Use of Cookies

Our Site may pass a "cookie" (a string of information that is sent by a web site to be resident on your system's hard drive, and/or temporarily in your computer's memory blocks). The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a particular page. The Site may use cookies in on-line catalogs to keep track of your status and contents of your shopping cart. or to retain information gathered in cookies to allow you access to password-protected areas of the Site. You may set your browser to decline cookies. If you do so, however, you may not be able to fully experience some interactive features of the Site.

### Pixel Tags Or Beacons

In addition to cookies, we also collect Aggregate Information through the use of "tracking pixels," also known as "beacons." A tracking pixel is a transparent graphic image (usually 1 pixel x 1 pixel) that is placed on a web page and, in combination with a cookie, allows for the collection of information regarding the use of the web page that contains the tracking pixel. We use tracking pixels to tell when an advertisement has been clicked on or otherwise interacted with, and use that information to judge which advertisements are more appealing to users. In some cases, we use third party service providers to help us collect and analyze this information. You can also generally opt-out of receiving personalized ads from third party advertisers and ad networks who are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) or who follow the Digital Advertising Alliance's Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising by visiting the opt-out pages on the [NAI website](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) and [DAA website](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

### How We Protect Your Information

We are committed to protecting the information we receive from you. However, Birchbox will not be liable for disclosures of your Personal Information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties. We have undertaken commercially reasonable efforts to prevent unauthorized Internet access to visitor data retained in our servers, however, due to the inherent open nature of the Internet, Birchbox cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or any information provided online, and you do so at your own risk. Users must accept all risks associated with any data transmission, including the risk that their Personal Information may be intercepted in transit.

The Site encrypts your credit card number and other Personal Information using secure socket layer (SSL) technology to provide for the secure transmission of the information from your PC to our servers. In addition, only those employees and third parties who need access to you information in order to perform their duties are allowed such access.

### Accessing and Updating Your Personal Information and Preferences

If you are a registered user, you may access and update your registration information and your preferences to receive email or other communications from us by sending an email to info@birchbox.com.

You may also update or change your Personal Information or Preferences by sending email to info@birchbox.com. We will take commercially reasonable steps to implement your opt-out requests promptly, but you may still receive communications from us for up to ten business days as we process your request.

While we make efforts to accommodate requests to restrict our use of your information, we reserve the right to delete all or any portion of customer information if we are not able to reasonably accommodate a requested restriction.

### Enforcement and Dispute Resolution

Birchbox uses a self-assessment approach to assure compliance with this privacy policy and periodically verifies that the policy is accurate, comprehensive for the information intended to be covered, prominently displayed, completely implemented and accessible and in conformity with the Principles. We encourage interested persons to raise any concerns using the contact information provided and we will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of Personal Information in accordance with the Principles.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

### Children's Privacy and Parental Controls

This Site and the App are not intended for persons under the age of 13, and we have no intention of collecting or soliciting Personal Information from persons under the age of 13. If you are not 13 or older, you are not authorized to use the Site or the App. Parents should be aware that there are parental control tools available online that you can use to prevent your children from submitting information online without parental permission or from accessing material that is harmful to minors. If a child under age 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will use all reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

### Links To Third Party Sites

Our Site may contain links to other web sites, including our affiliated or co-branded web sites. Other web sites may also reference or link to our Site. These "other" domains (web sites) are not controlled by Birchbox. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Site to read the privacy policies of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. We do not endorse, screen or approve, and are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other web sites. Visiting these other web sites is at your own risk.

### Site, App, and Store Terms and Conditions

Use of this Site, App, and Store is governed by, and subject to, the legal notices contained in our Terms and Conditions. Your use, or access, of the Site, App, or Store constitutes your agreement to be bound by these provisions. **IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THESE TERMS YOU MAY NOT ACCESS OR OTHERWISE USE THE SITE, THE APP, OR THE STORE.**

### Privacy Policy Changes

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this policy at any time. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post the revised Privacy Policy here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we may disclose it to anyone. Any changes will be consistent with the stated Principles of the Safe Harbor Agreement. Your continued use of the Site, App, and Store indicates your assent to the Privacy Policy as posted. Please check this page periodically for changes to this Privacy Policy. If we make any change to this Privacy Policy that we in our sole discretion deem material, we will notify you in a manner we deem appropriate.

If you have any questions about the Birchbox.com Privacy Policy please contact us at:

Birchbox Inc  
28 East 28th Street  
11th Floor  
New York, NY 10016  
(877) 487-7272  
info@birchbox.com

#### United States of America

Our Site, App, and Store are maintained in the United States of America. By using the Site, App, or Store you authorize the export of Personal Information to the USA and its storage and use as specified in this policy. Effective Date: This Privacy Policy is effective and was last updated on Decemeber, 12, 2016.

Get a monthly box of five personalized beauty samples. 

Get a monthly box of personalized grooming samples, plus a stylish accessory.
